# JAMES LOIZOU

https://github.com/jloizou/Projects https://portfolio-36197.web.app/

Hi! My name is James Loizou,

When I left University I wanted to find something which I could truly sink my teeth into and be challenged on a day-to-day basis, I taught myself for two months before taking a leap of faith into an immersive course and have come out with a real passion and hunger to learn!

Through lockdown I have loved to be social, play music and sport but what has really kept me getting out of bed in the morning with a smile has been Frontend Development.

I would love to use this skill working for you!

My Tech Stack is as follows:



















# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT**

# TRAINEE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, \_NOLOGY, REMOTE

The \_nology course was particularly enticing due to its inclusion of a practical client project, while giving me the opportunity to build skills which were desired, practical and would allow me to build responsive, engaging full stack web apps. This course has been invaluable, when I started, I could just about create a html page with some CSS, but now I have gained

- The fundamentals of professional web development, thanks to my in-depth knowledge of React
- A scope for the wider development world, which allowed me to create an API and use it to create an image and text generator

In addition to the technical side, the course has given me a look into the life of a developer through

- Test-driven development, including writing and implementing our own tests
- An Agile work environment, including scrums, weekly sprints, and pair programming
- Responsiveness, accessibility and how to write clean code.

In the Agile environment, I had the opportunity to lead my own team for the penultimate week of the client project; which entailed running the sprints, communicating directly with the client, and coordinating the project.

## 25/05/2018 - 25/05/2019

## Startup company, Ethical Beans

I was a part of the creation of a small coffee company, where I have undertaken many different roles, from licensing to a Barista to logo design. Including a trip to Amsterdam where I met with suppliers personally. The company has been put on hold indefinitely, but I have gained real confidence in my adaptability and my hunger to learn and master problems that set me back initially. Ethical Bean presented me with daunting challenges, such as giving a lecture at my university; but I found a true satisfaction in breaking them down and giving them my all until I excelled. I found the environment of a start-up to be incredibly

motivating and truly exciting! Having such a direct impact on the path and performance of the company was an honor and something which I thoroughly enjoyed.

#### **DECEMBER 2017 - DECEMER 2018**

# **HOSPITALITY, AT YOUR SERVICE**

My position was fluid, from serving canapes and champagne to royals to waitering for the biggest dinner event in London in the Royal Albert Hall. I needed to adapt to different roles and deliver a professional service while keeping morale up, especially in the longer shifts. This has left me with an effective skill in keeping calm and positive in tough situations which serves me well when stonewalled by a bug when coding.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **FINISHED 2020**

## **HISTORY BA 2:1, COVENTRY UNIVERSITY**

History at Coventry developed my proficiency in breaking down problems into small steps through tackling difficult questions. In attending the regular seminars, I was able to develop strong communication and problem-resolution skills through debating and being a mediator between hot-headed students. My time at Coventry showed me that what motivates me is tangible, unopinionated problems where I can take the initiative and come up with creative solutions.

#### **FINISHED 2017**

# A-LEVELS BBD, WREN ACADEMY SIXTH FORM

B In History and Economics, D in Physics

## **FINISHED 2015**

GCSE 6 B'S 4 A'S, WREN ACADEMY

## **SKILLS**

- I thrive in a team-based environment
- I keep calm in pressured situations
- I have a drive to master problems that, at first, seem insurmountable
- I'm a smiley character, and I pride myself in maintaining optimism in tough situations!

# **INTERESTS**

- I am a self-taught guitarist; I have been playing for two years and I am loving it! Letting lose my creative side has been a great way to keep my mental wellbeing up by de-stressing after a long day. At the moment, John Mayer's music is a huge source of inspiration.
- I am a huge fan of martial arts! I practice and watch it whenever I can, specifically boxing and Muay Thai. As they are a way for me to push my comfort zone out and develop my confidence in tackling daunting situations